《僵尸国度》前情提要
Previously on Z Nation.
我们去和大队会合
We're gonna meet up with the team.
送摩菲到实验室去
We're gonna get Murphy to that lab.
然后找到治愈僵尸病毒的方法
And then we are going to cure this virus.
那是个谎话  而且这谎话会害死我们的
It's a lie, and it's gonna get us both killed.
那我也情愿因相信这个谎话而死
Well then I'd rather die believing in a lie
总好过没有信仰地苟且活着
than live believing in nothing.
艾迪  艾迪  艾迪
Addy! Addy! Addy!
坚持住  艾迪
Stay with me, Addy!
-发生什么了  -我知道那些闪回是怎么回事了
- What happened?  - I know what the flashbacks are.
我杀了我妈妈
I killed my mom.
我们谁也不会丢下其他人不管
We don't leave each other behind.
我是为你而回  我以后也会这样做
I came back for you. I'll always come back for you.
你确定市民Z让我们下到这里来吗
Are you sure Citizen Z said we should be down here?
是啊  他是这么说的
Yeah, that's what he said.
听到了吗
Hear that?
你怎么看
What do you think, huh?
是死是活  是人还是丧尸
Dead? Alive? Human? Zombie?
死人一个
Dead.
这边  这边  这边  这边
Here, here, here, here, here.
逮到你们了
Bingo.
歌词改编自一段美国跳长绳时唱的童谣
灰姑娘穿上了一身黄
Cinderella dressed in yella.
走到了楼上去亲暖男
Went upstairs to kiss a fella.
她嗑完了药
She took a pill.
又丢了节操
Lost her frills.
快来数数她宰了
How many zombies
几只丧尸
does she kill?
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four.
你就不能给他们个痛快吗
You couldn't just give them mercy?
那还有什么意思
What fun would that be?
那是什么
What was that?
我不知道
I don't know.
去看看
Come on.
嘘
Shhhh.
站在那别动
Hold it right there.
哦  原来是奇葩二人组啊
Oh, it's the damn wonder twins.
伙计们
Guys.
搞毛线啊
What?
原来是奇葩...
The wonder...
嘿
Hey!
天呐
Oh my!
哥从来  我是说真的  一百万年做梦也想不到
Never, I mean never, ever, in a million years,
还有机会能再看到你们
truly did I think I'd see you guys again.
市民Z让你们到这的吗
Citizen Z send you guys?
是啊  他说这有食物
Yeah. He told us there was food and
还说有个叫切斯特的人能帮我们逃出去
somebody named Chester who could help us out.
是啊他也这么跟我们说了  真怀疑有没有这么个人
Yeah, he told us that too. We're starting to have our doubts.
好吧  这个人应该能帮得上忙  我们先往那边走
Okay, well he should be, you know what, right down there.
出发吧
Let's hit it.
她怎么了这是
What happened to her?
她之前被一个带刺的铁丝网伤到了
She got caught on a piece of barbed wire.
现在伤口都感染了
Now it's all infected.
有人吗
Hello!
看来我们找到切斯特了
Well I guess we found Chester.
你好啊  切斯特
Hello, Chester.
看来有人在末世过得不是很开心哦
Somebody got up on the wrong side of the apocalypse.
你们俩在外面的时候都发生了什么
What happened to you guys out there?
她弄明白了一些事情
She's working out some stuff.
你也知道  有些事情在脑海中就是挥之不去
You know how things can catch up with you.
切斯特
Chester?
你找到他们了吗  找到我的小队了吗
You got them yet? You got my team?
有人吗
Hello? Anyone?
是沃伦吗
Warren?
艾迪  这真是...
Addy, it's...
看上面
Hey, hey, hey! Up here!
是你们的老朋友市民Z
It's your old pal, Citizen Z.
大家都在呀
Oh, it's everyone.
大家好
Hi, everyone. Hi!
艾迪还是一如既往那么美艳
Addy, looking gorgeous as always.
你一定就是麦克了
Oh, hey uh, you must be Mack.
呵呵  我原本以为你个子会再高一点呢
Kinda thought you'd be taller.
你这么乳臭未干也真是出乎我意料
I thought you'd be old enough to shave.
摩菲  上前头来让我看清楚你
Hey, Murphy. Squeeze in so I can see you.
你看起来不错  先生
Yeah, lookin' good, sir.
你们猜怎么着  我这里有个好消息
So guess what? I've got good news.
加利福尼亚重新上线了
California's back.
大部分都还活着也连上网了
They're alive and online, well most of them.
他们准备好迎接你们了
But they're getting ready for you,
研发疫苗之梦没有破灭
and the dream is alive.
任务继续  衷心感谢你们
The mission is a go, thanks to yours truly.
这消息不错是吧
That's good news, right?
好消息应该是有一包奥利奥
Good news would be a package of Oreos
和几加仑的牛奶
and a couple gallons of milk.
没错  抱歉
Oh, oh yeah, right. Sorry.
在这个大厅下面左手边的那个房间里
Down the same hall, next door on your left.
里面应该有你们需要的所有东西
Should be everything that you need.
能再次见到你们我真是太高兴了
I can't tell you how good it is to see you all again.
我也很高兴你能见到我们还活着  孩子
Good to see us too, kid.
这里到底是哪里
Hey, what was this place anyway?
中情局黑牢
CIA black site.
像是水刑和《猎杀本·拉登》里那样的黑牢吗
Oh, like waterboarding, Zero Dark Thirty, black site?
是的  是切斯特告诉我的
Yeah, I kinda thought it would be obvious
我还以为挺明显的
from what Chester told me.
那个老家伙在哪里
So where is the old crackpot anyway?
天呐  真不幸
Oh man. Bummer.
沃伦  这段路开慢点好吗
Whoa, Warren. Slow up here, will ya?
一个孩子而已
It's just a kid.
这可不是孩子  这是个被碾到的僵尸
That is not a kid. It's zombie road kill.
距盐湖城251英里
十点钟方向
Ten o'clock.
又来一个孩子
Another kid.
早就不是了
Not anymore.
停车
Stop.
沃伦停车  只是个孩子而已  停车
Warren, stop. It's just a boy. Stop.
别  你弄疼我了  别
Don't! You're hurting me! Don't!
艾迪
Addy!
干嘛
What?!
该哪哪去
Fine!
小心  前面这孩子还活着
Heads up, we got a live one.
又是个穿着古怪花衬衫一脸悲伤的孩子
Another sad kid in a weird flowered shirt.
我来对付这个
I got this one.
你还好吗
You okay?
就是有点口渴
A little thirsty is all.
应该的
Of course.
稍等
Hold on.
给我水壶
Water.
谢了
Thanks.
喝吧孩子
Here you go, champ.
谢谢你  女士
Thanks, ma'am.
你可以叫我罗伯塔
You can call me Roberta.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
我叫山姆
I'm Sam.
山姆
Sam.
你妈知道你自己一个人在外吗
Does your mom know you're out here all by yourself?
我要去盐湖城看我爸
I'm going to Salt Lake City to see my dad.
这可不是个好主意
That's not a good idea.
不  不对
Yes, it is.
我已经长大了  我终于可以见我爸了
I'm old enough now. I finally get to meet my dad.
路太远了  况且路上也不安全
It's too far. It's not safe.
路不算远
It's not too far.
布纳恩和达克斯已经到那里了
Brennan and Dax are already there.
山姆
Sam.
盐湖城已经被僵尸占领了
Salt Lake City's been overrun by zombies.
是哦  我知道了
Yeah, right.
等等  山姆
Uh, wait, wait, Sam.
你说的没错
You're right.
你已经长大了  可以去见你的父亲了
You are old enough to go see your dad.
但是还有个事
But here's the thing.
我们的食物吃光了
We've run out of food.
你能帮帮我们吗
Can you help us?
我的朋友海伦可以帮到你们
My friend Helen could help you get some food.
很好
Cool.
你能告诉我们他们住在哪里吗
Will you show us where they live?
这样吧
Tell you what.
你带我们去找你朋友
You take us there,
我们开车带你去盐湖城
we will drive you to Salt Lake City.
好吧
Okay.
摩菲  让个地方
Murphy, move.
你好
Hey there.
你好  小伙子  我叫麦克
Hey man, I'm Mack.
蒙蒂塞洛  犹他州
就在那边
Just up there.
非请莫入
有人在家吗
Anybody home?
看着好像没人
Doesn't look like it.
麦克  你先下去侦查一下
Mack, you want to check it out?
好的
Yeah.
回到车里去
Get back in the truck!
这里不欢迎你
You're not welcome here!
慢着  别激动
Hold on, hold on!
没事的
It's okay.
我们毫无恶意  我们只是...
We're friendly. We just...
停停停  别开火  先听我把话说完好吗
Stop! Stop! It's fine! Just listen to me for a second!
我们有
We have...
我记得你说她们很友善  山姆
I thought you said they were friendly, Sam.
别开火  求你们别开枪
Stop! Don't shoot! Please!
你们的孩子在我们车上
We have your boy!
山姆跟我们在一起
We have Sam!
停火
Hold your fire!
打开大门
Open the gate.
海伦女士  没事的  他们只是想找些食物
Ms. Helen, it's okay. They just need food.
他们人不错
They're nice.
很高兴见到你  山姆
It's good to see you, Sam.
你进去找你妈吧
Why don't you go inside and find your mother?
我相信她现在急着想见你
I'm sure she's anxious to see you.
谢谢你们能带他回来
Thank you for bringing him back.
有时我们的孩子得了幽居病
Sometimes our kids get cabin fever
然后决定要外出探险
and decide to go exploring.
你怎么了
What's wrong with you?
伤口感染了
It's infected.
那可能很危险
Oh, that could be dangerous.
确实
Yeah, it could.
我们可以帮助你
We can help you.
你们现在到了仁慈姐妹会
You've arrived at the Sisters of Mercy.
大姐  我们赶时间呢
Anytime now!
你不想留下也可以
You don't have to stay!
他必须得留下
Yes, he does.
我们是伙伴
We're a team.
是吗
You are?
是的
Yes.
不管是不是伙伴
Well, team or not,
如果你想留下  你们就必须分开
if you want to stay here, you'll have to split up.
这里只让女人和孩子进
Women and children only here.
你和你的朋友可以进
You can go inside with your friend.
但男人们必须待在墙外
But your men will have to stay outside the wall.
我们给你们二十四小时
We'll give you 24 hours.
你们可以休息  吃东西  然后上路
You can rest, get some food, and then you'll leave us.
你的想法合情合理
That's very fair of you.
请问你怎么称呼
And you are?
海伦  你呢
Helen. And you?
罗伯塔·沃伦中尉  密苏里国民警卫队的
Lieutenant Roberta Warren. Missouri National Guard.
艾迪
Addy.
别担心
Don't worry.
我会照顾她的
I got her.
没错  这糟透了
Yeah, this blows.
你能帮她吗
Can you help her?
她的腿感染了  带他去医务室
She has an infected leg. Take her to the infirmary.
你真漂亮
You're pretty.
你好
Hi.
想看看我的胡萝卜吗
Want to see my carrots?
当然
Sure.
是我自己种的
I planted them myself.
在这吗
Here?
对
Yep.
这里真美
It's beautiful here.
来吧
Come on.
我帮你
Here you go.
谢谢
Thanks.
看这个  看这里面所有的花
Now look at this one, and look at all the flowers in it.
在这里  我们自己种蔬菜
Here we grow our own vegetables.
后面我们还有鸡和牛
We have chickens and cows out back.
牛  你们有牛奶吗
Cows? You get milk?
牛奶  黄油  酸奶
Milk, butter, yogurt.
对你们来说最重要的是青霉素
Most importantly for you, penicillin.
是艾米自己做的  她以前是药剂师
Amy makes it herself. She used to be a chemist.
厨房的琳娜
Lina's in the kitchen,
会告诉你们  哪里可以清洁一下自己
she'll show you where you can wash up.
另外  我希望你能一起来吃午餐
And I hope you'll join us for our mid-day meal.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢谢
错了  应该是  手背  手掌  拍
No. It's back, front, clap,
右  然后左
right, then left.
抱歉  我很久没玩过这个了
Sorry, I haven't done this in forever.
我妈妈很久之前教过我
My mom taught me a really long time ago.
她人好吗
Is she nice?
是的  是的  她人很好
Yeah, yeah, she is.
再来一次
Let's try again.
不管是谁建立了这个地方
Whoever built this place
他一定是预见到大灾变的到来了
must've seen the Apocalypse coming.
这里简直完美
It's perfect.
是我丈夫建立的
That was my husband.
他的处世哲学是
His philosophy was that we become
我们应该绝对地自给自足  脱离尘世
absolutely self-sufficient and off the grid.
你丈夫吗
Your husband?
他不在了
He's gone.
像其他人一样
Like the others.
这些女人呢
All these women?
吉娜和埃米琳是我的好姐妹
Well Zina and Emmeline were my sister wives.
亚蒙死后  我们只有彼此与这个地方
And when Ammon went, we had each other and this place.
在我们发现这些女人前  她们都很不幸
These other women weren't so lucky 'til we found them.
现在她们安全了
Now they're safe.
她们自由了
They're free.
再吃点草莓吗
More strawberries?
不吃了   我...
No. I...
我得去找一下卡桑德拉
I think I'm gonna go look in on Cassandra
看看她怎么样了
and see how she's doing.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you.  - Of course.
这就是你们种的胡萝卜吗  很好吃
So these are the carrots you grew? They're delicious.
感觉好些了吗  谢谢你
Feeling better? Thank you.
好些了
Starting to.
还记得山姆和我们说他要去哪吗
Remember what Sam told us about where he was going?
去盐湖城找他爸爸
Salt Lake City to see his dad.
艾米有个比山姆大一些的儿子
Amy has a son a little older than Sam.
他现在不在这里
He's not here.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
他也去盐湖城找爸爸了吗
Went to Salt Lake City to see his dad?
女孩都在  而男孩长到13岁都离开了
The girls stay here, but all the boys leave when they turn 13.
她是这么说的
That's what she said.
她们看起来很幸福
They seem so happy.
恩  有点幸福过头了
Yeah, maybe a little too happy.
太善良的人总会吓到我
Nice people always scare me.
等你好起来  我们一起离开这
Let's get you well, and let's get out of here.
这里的女人让我毛骨悚然
All these women give me the creeps.
那个金发女人一直盯着我
That blonde one keeps looking at me.
哥们  可千万别低估了自己
Oh man, don't get down on yourself like that.
你可是一块抢手的大肥肉
You are a perfect hunk of man meat,
你可别忘了
and don't you ever forget it.
哈哈  做好你的本分吧
Ha, ha. Don't quit your day job.
那里面真的只有女人吗
Is there really all women in there?
是啊  小万万  你好好幻想一下吧
Yeah. Enjoy your imagination, kid.
你也许只能想想罢了
That's probably all you're gonna get.
多克  有一点我不能理解
You know what I don't understand, Doc?
男人都死到哪里去了
What the hell happened to all their men?
也许我们可以问问她
Well maybe we can ask her.
来自天堂的天使
Angels from heaven.
那是派吗
Is that pie?
蓝莓派  额...  我我我...我自己做的
Blueberry. Ummm, I, I, I made it by myself.
你们知道...
Do you guys know where the...
另一个人去哪了  那个...
the other one is? The one with the with the a
头发和眼睛...  他...
the hair and those eyes? He...
一万  别让人打扰哥  末世结束再叫醒哥
10K, Hold my calls, wake me up after the apocalypse
我要去给他送一块派
I'm gonna go give him a piece of this.
什么事
What?
吃派吗
Pie?
孩子  走开
Beat it, kid.
走呀
Beat it!
你喜欢吗
You like that?
没关系  有人让你受伤了吗
It's okay. Somebody hurt you?
嗯呐嗯呐  姐了解  姐全都了解
Yeah? I know. I know.
爹地
Daddy.
你需要我的照顾
You need me to take care of you.
我想让你停下
Part of me wants you to stop.
可是我又很想吃派
But part of me really needs the pie.
食人族吗
Cannibals?
很抱歉你遇到了这种事
I'm so sorry that happened to you.
我真的想说我很震惊
And I wish I could say I was surprised.
天呐
Man.
他无法控制自己
He can't help himself.
动物的本能掌控了他
The animal instinct takes over.
滥杀
Kill,
破坏
destroy,
强奸
rape.
现在又是这个瘟疫  这个病毒
Now this disease, this virus.
雄性荷尔蒙才是地球上最毒的毒药
Testosterone is the most toxic chemical on Earth.
而你挺过了这一切  来到了这里
And you survived through it all. Now you're here.
我运气好
I was really lucky.
一开始我就遇到了麦克
I met Mack on the first night.
我看是他运气好
I think he was the lucky one.
这是什么
What about this?
肯定有故事
This is special.
没错  你怎么知道的
Yeah, yeah. How'd you know?
告诉我
Tell me.
我说不出
I can't.
太沉重了
It's too much for you.
我看得出
I can see that.
你可以告诉我  告诉我吧
You can tell me. Just tell me.
是我妈妈
It was my mom.
还有我弟弟
And my brother.
我不得不...
And I had to...
两个都是
both of them.
可怜的姑娘啊
Oh, my sweet, sweet, sweet girl.
看开吧  释怀就好了
Let it go. Just let it all go.
我能告诉你件事吗
Can I tell you something?
你再也不会遭遇这样的惨剧了
You don't ever have to go through that again.
这个地方  我们姐妹
This place, our sisters,
我们会保护你的
we're protected from that.
我们用得上你这样的姑娘
We could use a woman like you.
聪明  有本事  心地善良
Smart, resourceful, caring.
你和其他人不一样  你很特别
You're not like the others. You're special.
我看得出
I can see that.
看来有新姐妹加入我们了
Hmmm, looks like we have a new sister.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
这位是泰莎
This is Tessa.
泰莎  欢迎你
Tessa, welcome.
你到家了
You're home now.
你安全了
You're safe.
没事了
It's okay.
再也不会有人伤害你了
No one can hurt you here.
这就是我们存在的意义
This is why we exist.
我们建立了一个
We provide a place that is safe
不受男性暴力侵害的地方
from the violent destructive world of men.
而且我们会惩罚那些施暴者
And we bring the perpetrators to justice.
那就是我们的意义
That is our purpose.
带上来
Bring him.
你叫什么
What is your name?
咬我啊  婊子
Bite me, Bitch.
婊子
Hmmm, Bitch.
好名字  你用着合适
I like that. It suits you.
是时候让你见识见识正义了  婊子
Well it's time that you learn about justice, Bitch.
带下去
Take him away.
你该来看看
You should see this.
他会有什么下场
What's gonna happen to him?
正义
Justice.
你敢伤女人  你就得死  这就是规矩
You harm a woman, you die. That's our rule.
泰莎
Tessa?
去吧  泰莎
Now, Tessa.
不
No!
他是个坏人
He was a bad man.
你还好吗
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
泰莎说外面还有两个姐妹
Tessa said there are two sisters still out there.
你可以帮我们解救她们
We could use your help to free them.
当然可以
Of course.
艾迪
Addy.
你确定你要去吗
You sure you're up to that?
沃伦
Warren.
我们都有可能像她们一样需要帮助
Any one of us could be those sisters.
我要加入
I'm in.
好极了
Wonderful.
好吧  我也去
Yeah, you got me too.
你不必这样
You don't have to.
没关系
No, no, no.
我要支持我的姐妹们
I always got my sister's back.
我们得跟这些人撇清关系  小伙子们  上路吧
We got to burn this joint, boys. Time to motor.
多克  等会  大哥  怎么了
Whoa, Doc. Hold on, man. What Is it?
你看见什么了
What'd you see?
僵尸
Zombie.
熊
Bear.
有人来了
Someone's coming.
她们不会就这样扔下我们不管了吧
They wouldn't just leave us, would they?
不可能  艾迪不会离开我的
No, Addy doesn't go anywhere without me.
对不起  伙计
Sorry, pal.
她刚才就离开你了
She just did.
他们来了
Here they come.
遇到什么麻烦了吗  亲爱的
You got a problem there, darlin'?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
你们这样很危险啊
Kinda dangerous, ain't it?
这么漂亮的两个姑娘
Two pretty little gals like you,
怎么能独自上路呢
travelin' all alone?
外面可不怎么安全
It's not safe out here.
要不这样吧
I'll tell you what.
跟我说说你们要往哪个方向走
Why don't you tell me where you're headed,
侧三轮上的小伙子能帮你们检查引擎
and Sidecar here can have a look at that engine.
手举起来  先生们
Hands up, gentlemen.
你们的小把戏就到此结束吧
Your little game is over.
等等  别这样  别这样
Wait, wait, wait. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
我跟他们不是一伙的  他们只不过...
I'm not really with them. They just...
-我被困住了  他们把我救出来的  -闭嘴
- I was stranded, and they helped me out. - Shut up!
把枪放下
Drop your guns.
你想得美  甜心
That ain't happening, sweetheart.
别开枪  别开枪
Hold your fire! Hold your fire.
看见没
You see, huh?
我可是个讲理的人
I'm a reasonable man.
有什么事情我们可以好好商量
I'm sure we can come to some kind of an arrangement.
你直接告诉我你想要什么吧
Why don't you just tell me what you want?
我来问你
Let me ask.
这两个女孩是自愿跟着你的吗
These girls with you voluntarily?
恐怕不是吧
Didn't think so.
女士们
Ladies.
嘿  听我说
Hey, hey, listen to me.
那里有个挂包  里面装的全是奥施康定[止痛药]
That saddlebag, it's full of oxycontin.
你可以全拿走
You can take it.
我没兴趣
Not interested.
哪有怒气冲冲的婊子不做交易的
What kind of a raging bitch doesn't want to make a deal?
我就不
This one.
艾迪  过来帮帮忙
Hey, Addy. We could use your help over here.
伸张正义的时刻到了
It's time for some justice.
杀掉一个
Shoot one.
要致命伤  但不要爆头
A mortal wound, anywhere but the head.
其余的人自然就解决了
The rest will take care of themselves.
不是这个
Oh, not this one.
杀另一个
The other one.
艾迪  等一下
Addy, wait.
我发誓  不是我干的  求你了  不是我
I swear. I...it wasn't me. I... please. Please. I wasn't...
真的有必要这么做吗
Is this really necessary?
艾迪  别开枪
Addy, don't do this.
你不会想与我为敌的  好妹妹
You don't want to get in my way, sister.
求你了  我  我发誓  我什么都没做
Please, I...I swear. I swear. I wasn't gonna do anything.
他说谎
He's lying.
记得食人族绑架了你吧
Remember the cannibal remember when he kidnapped.
还记得吧
Remember.
还记得托拜亚斯吧
Remember Tobias.
还记得他绑架了你吧
Remember when he kidnapped.
天啊  不不  不要啊
Oh, God! No! No! No!
好孩子
Good girl.
该走了
It's time to go.
我们得离开这
We got to get out of here.
我知道  我看到那头熊了
I know. I saw the bear.
那都不算事
That's not the problem.
如果连僵尸熊都不算事了  那还有什么
If a zombie bear isn't the problem, what is?
我要见她
I need to see her.
她在一个很奇怪的地方
She's in a weird place.
我也去过那
I've been there.
将她带出来可不是件容易的事
It's not gonna be easy to get her back.
没关系  但是没有她我不走
Well it's fine, but I'm not leaving here without her.
你们做好准备
You guys just get ready.
我尽全力将她带出来
I'll do my best to get her out.
但你可能还是要做出一个选择
But you may have a choice to make.
我知道这不容易
I know what you did seemed hard.
当我杀死自己的丈夫
I felt the same way
获得自由的时候也有同样的感觉
when I freed myself from my husband.
他当时也声称是无辜的
He said he was innocent, too.
我们从小到大
You know we were both raised to
一直坚信
believe all the rules, that
他们是好人  是真理
they were good and true and
是上帝的恩赐
from God.
在我差点死于生第五个孩子之后
And after I almost died after my fifth child,
我就开始不再相信这一切
I started not to believe.
我不想再生孩子了
I didn't want anymore children.
我不需要他了
I didn't want him.
但这些想法不符合那些信条
And that didn't square with the rules.
所以他就打我
So he beat me.
我的鼻子  胳膊还有肋骨都被他打折了
He broke my nose and my arms, ribs.
这还不算最糟的
But that's not even the worst story
这里的姐妹们还有更惨的
that you'll hear from the women in here.
我们现在就得离开
We got to go now.
你看见艾迪了吗
You seen Addy?
没有
No.
我们会在出去的路上找到她的
We will find her on the way out.
我会没事的
I'll be fine.
希望如此
Hope so.
会没事的
I will.
你是从外面进来的
You've been out there.
你知道外面是什么样子的
You know what it's like.
我也...  不知道
I just... don't know
我应该怎么做
what I'm supposed to do anymore.
我做不到无动于衷
I can't un-see any of it.
那些人
The people,
甚至是僵尸
even the zombies.
你承受得太多了
It's too much
任何人都会这样
for anyone.
你需要休息
You need rest.
平静
Peace.
留在这里
Stay here.
成为我们家庭中的一员
Be a part of our family.
我不能离开麦克
I can't leave Mack.
我不能
I can't.
我爱他
I love him.
我知道你爱他  亲爱的
I know you do, sweetheart.
所以让你眼睁睁看着他死会更痛苦的
So it'll hurt all that much more when you have to watch him die.
他总有一天会死去
And one day he will die.
而你将会是那个
And it will be you
给他"施与仁慈"的人
that has to give him mercy.
是啊
Yeah.
我要怎么跟他说
How do I tell him?
我该说什么
What do I say?
我来教你怎么跟他说
I'll tell you what to say.
好的
Okay.
艾迪
Addy
能找个地方说几句话吗
Hey, can we go talk somewhere real quick?
好  当然可以
Uh, yeah. Yeah, of course.
里面是什么样子
So what's it like in there?
听上去有些怪异  毕竟一个僵尸...
Sounds a little weird, I mean a zombie...
不  不  不  麦克  里面...
Uh, no, no, no, no, no. Mack, it is...
里面很美
It's so beautiful.
要是你能看见就好了
I wish you could see it.
是啊  我也希望能看到
Yeah, I wish I could too.
跟外面的世界截然不同
It's so different from out here.
让我有了安全感
I feel safe.
我已经很久没有这样的感觉了
I haven't felt that in such a long time.
不错  很好
Good. That's good.
我很高兴...
I'm glad. It's...
对你来说  离开那里应该挺难的
I'm sure it's gonna be hard to leave.
这就是我想跟你谈的
That's what I wanted to talk to you about.
这一切太沉重了
It's too much.
我撑不下去了  麦克
I can't do it anymore, Mack.
但是  艾迪...
But Addy...
我不能跟你一起留下来
I can't stay with you here.
我需要休息了
I need to rest.
我做不到
I can't.
没有你  我什么都做不了
I can't do this without you.
不  不  艾迪  艾迪  拜托  拜托
No, no, no, no, no, no. Addy. Addy, come on. Come on.
我爱你  我...  你不能...
I love you. I... I... Don't you...
麦克  我真的很爱你
Mack, I love you so much.
我不能再回去  看着你死
I cannot go back out there and watch you die.
我不会死的
I'm not gonna die.
不  你会死
Yes, you will.
我们都会死
We all will.
我希望留存在我脑海里的是你现在的模样
And this is how I want to remember you.
麦克  我不能再夺去我心爱之人的生命了
Mack, I cannot kill somebody I love ever again.
你不走  我也不会走的  艾迪
I'm not going back out there without you, Addy.
我不会  我做不到
I'm not. I can't.
这样对大家都好
This is for the best.
艾迪  艾迪  等等  等一下
Addy. Addy, wait. Wait a minute.
摩菲怎么办
What about Murphy, huh?
任务怎么办
And the mission?
你说过  怀揣着信仰死去
You said, you said you would rather
总好过无所信仰地活着
die believing in something than live believing in nothing.
我得走了
I have to go.
看着我  看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
我理解  我懂  你...
I understand. I do. You're...
你妈妈的事让你很难过  人之常情
You're upset about your mom. Of course. Of course.
这件事太可怕了  简直是个悲剧
It's horrible. I mean it's, it's beyond horrible.
但是你会熬过去的
But you're gonna get through this.
你不是这样的
That's not who you are.
你是个好人  你很强大
You're a good person. You're, you're, you're strong.
你很强  你不需要海伦
You're strong. You don't need Helen
还有什么脑残邪教
and some stupid cult.
对不起
I'm sorry.
艾迪  艾迪  你不能这么做
Addy, Addy, Addy. You can't do this.
-麦克  -你不能离开我  这样很疯狂
- Mack. - You can't leave me. This is crazy.
-麦克  -艾迪  等下
- Mack. - Addy, wait.
-麦克  放开我  -艾迪  听我说
- Mack, let me go. - Addy, just listen to me.
听我说  好吗
Just listen to me, okay?
-麦克  -你没考虑清楚
- Mack. - You're not thinking clearly.
你弄疼我了
You're hurting me!
等下  艾迪
Wait. Addy.
艾迪
Addy!
等下
Wait!
艾迪
Addy!
喂  艾迪
Hey. Addy!
艾迪
Addy!
请跟我们说话
Please talk to us!
拜托  艾迪
Come on, Addy!
也许我可以帮忙
Maybe I could help?
我想我们受够你的帮助了
I think we've had enough of your help.
艾迪
Addy?
是我
It's me.
开门
Open the door.
艾迪
Addy?
别碰我
Don't touch me.
摩菲在哪里  我们需要帐篷
Where's Murphy? We need the tent.
他跟那个女孩还在里面
Uh, he's still in it with that girl.
她还在里面吗
She's still in there?
派对结束了 大家要上路了
Party's over, everyone. Time to go.
你从哪里弄来香烟的
Where'd you get a cigarette?
老爹想要什么
Whatever daddy needs,
就有什么
daddy gets.
现在要上路了  亲爱的
Yeah, well time to go now, sweetheart.
来吧  站起来走过去
Come on. Up and at 'em.
谢谢  老兄
Thanks, man.
否则她不会离开的
Thought she'd never leave.
惊喜吧
Surprise.
来吧  告诉她们
Go ahead. Tell them.
把你告诉我的告诉她们
Tell them what you told me.
我打定主意了
I've made up my mind.
我要跟海伦
I'm gonna stay here
留在这里
with Helen.
不行  艾迪
No. Addy.
大门出事了  我们需要你
Trouble at the gate. We need you.
你留在这里  你会没事的
You stay here. You'll be safe.
艾迪  我知道这地方感觉很安全
Addy, I know this place feels safe.
感觉很好
It feels good.
我遇到托拜亚斯时  也是这种感觉
Well that's how I felt when I met Tobias.
但并不真实
But it wasn't real.
我和你
You and me,
一起经历了很多
we've been through so much together.
艾迪生·卡弗
Addison Carver.
听我说
Listen to me.
一切都够了
Enough now.
你被卷入的这桩事儿
You got sucked into this thing,
你做出了你的努力
and you did something.
我们也都做出了努力
And we all do things.
但现在是时候离开了  现在
But it is time for us to go. Now.
我们全部
All of us.
你无需担心
You don't have to worry.
这现在就是我的家
I'm home now.
不
No.
她怎么出来的
How'd she get outside?
她在哪
Where is she?!
那高个子呢
The tall one?
你们的头头呢
Your leader?
我在这  你想要什么
I'm here! What do you want?
就是你  亲爱的
You, sweetheart.
我要你
I want you.
你乖乖把门打开
You open that gate
然后你乖乖出来
and you come out here.
咱们就好好聊聊
And we'll have a nice little conversation.
咱们和和气气的
All polite like.
杀了他
Shoot him.
我扣扳机可是出了名的快
I'm a real quick trigger.
你要是杀我
You shoot me,
她绝对跟着我一起陪葬
she's dead before I hit the ground.
五
Five.
四
Four.
三
Three.
二
Two.
一
One.
她会来的  是吧
She's coming, right?
当然  她会来的
Yes, she's coming.
没事的  艾迪
It's all right, Addy.
快过来吧
Come here, please.
艾迪
Addy.
求你了
Please?
我永远爱你  麦克
I will always love you, Mack.
咱们不来这一套
We don't do this.
咱们不能分开
We don't leave each other.
再见  麦克
Goodbye, Mack.
不
No.
你敢射他
You shot him?!
这是个警告  快给我滚
It's a warning. Get him out of here now.
趁姑奶奶们心情好
Before it gets worse.
拿上他的枪
Get his gun.
走吧
Come on.
艾迪
Addy!
-走吧  伙计  -艾迪
- Come on, buddy. - Addy!
-艾迪呢  -快走
- What about Addy? - Come on.
她不来了
She's not coming!
咱现在就走  多克
Let's go, Doc! Now!
停车
Stop the truck.
-不行  -快停车
- No. - Stop the truck!
继续开
Keep driving!
麦克  麦克  麦克
Mack, Mack, Mack.
我不能就这么走了
I can't.
好吧
Okay.
我不能
I can't.
上车
Get in!
蝴蝶蝴蝶  无忧无虑
Butterfly, butterfly, happy all day.
蝴蝶蝴蝶  飞飞飞飞
Butterfly, butterfly, fly fly away.
三只小蝴蝶  绕着你跳舞
Three little butterflies looking at you.
一只飞走了  还剩下两只
One flew away and then there were two.
两只小蝴蝶  晒着日光浴
Two little butterflies soaking up the sun.
一只飞走了  只剩下一只
One flew away and then there was one.
一直小蝴蝶  终日独徘徊
One little butterfly stayed all along.
蝴蝶飞走了  它们都走了
It flew away and then they were gone.
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译 米小勒   kiko   Marshal同学  CS小明漫画家   lottie  章鱼
翻译 我叫魏碧慧   蔡茸茸   S很爱笑   迷失仁慈姐妹会   小奶
时间轴   SumenQ   安妮   太太乐叽叽     后期   阿小小海
校对   米小勒       总监   米小勒
僵 尸
国 度
.
第一季 第十集